Contact

eyfisher@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/erika-fisher-msn-bsn-rn-79a755bb (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitals
Healthcare
Leadership

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Erika Fisher, MSN, BSN, RN

Assistant Director of Women's Services at Texas Children's Hospital Houston, Texas Area

Summary

Experienced Director/Manager with a broad range of business, healthcare, and clinical experience.

Recipient of multiple professional awards recognizing professional and customer service excellence. Awards include; excellent patient care, airman of the year, airmen of the quarter, and recipient of 12 military medals.

Current professional committees: Forms and Policy, Clinical Integration, and Patient Portal Steering Committee.

Core Competencies:

Biostatistics/Research, Finance, Human Resources, Strategic Planning, Health Care Policy, Health Care Administration, Health Care Law, Personnel Management, Managed Care Operations, Global Health, Postpartum, Newborn Nursery, Women's Care, Labor and Delivery, Precepting, Health Education, Record Management, Collaboration And Teamwork, Informatics and Technology, Communications And Information Management, Information Systems And Technology Support

Tools: Centricity, Mypaychex, Taleo, McKessen, OB Traceview, Epic, Microsoft Office software, High Performance Plan Learning Central and Talent Manager, Lawson Portal.

Experience

Texas Children's Hospital
Assistant Director of Women's Services
February 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Plan, organize and serve as primary direction for strategic planning as well as all daily operational related issues. Manage and oversee daily clinical and

business initiatives, uphold administrative and human resource activities for the designated clinical areas (Business Operations, Call Center, Reproductive Endocrinology and Infertility, Embryology, FFC Laboratory, Obstetrics and Gynecology, Urogynecology, Minimally Invasive Surgery, Reproductive Psychiatry, Infusion Center, Gynecologic Oncology, Menopause Center, Vulvovaginal health program), including providing 24 hour on call availability. Participates in, coordinates and ensures the delivery of high quality, patient and family centered care at the unit level. Responsible for supporting and implementing patient satisfaction initiatives/improvement efforts at service line level. Advocates for the delivery of high quality, family centered care at the department level and throughout the organization by establishing collaborative relationships with leadership. Due to unique positioning of hospital based clinics additionally interact, impact, and coordinate with multiple hospital based service lines to include labor and delivery, pharmacy, perioperative, inpatient, fetal center, infusion, women's imaging, nutrition, genetics, hospital admissions, revenue cycle.

Legacy Community Health
Director of Clinical Services
January 2014 - February 2017 (3 years 2 months)
Houston, Texas Area

Accountable for the financial and operational success of all assigned practices in the assigned geographic, specialty and defined group. Ensure the direction and implementation of operating policies and initiatives within the assigned groups- Business Operations, Obstetrics, Gynecology, Behavioral Health, Pediatrics, Ultrasound, Procedures, Laboratory, Eligibility, Nutrition, Urgent Care, Immunizations, Radiology, Maternal Fetal Medicine, Patient Education, Care Team Assistants (Case Management), and Social Services. Participate and assist practice managers to develop site-specific action plans, budgets and tactics for assigned practices.

Presbyterian Healthcare Services Women's Service Line Nurse 2009 - 2014 (5 years)

Combined experience of Post-Partum, Newborn Nursery, Women's Post-Op Care, and Labor and Delivery. Certified and trained as a preceptor to college students and new employees. Oversaw the lateral integration of care for patients and actively provided direct patient care in complex situations/ emergencies. Lead and promoted the Baby Friendly structure throughout the

women's service line. Recognized, multiple times, by patients and staff for providing exceptional care and attention to both the patient and family alike.

- Provided direct nursing care in accordance with established policies, procedures, and protocols of the organization. Recognized by staff and patients for providing quality/exceptional care.
- Dedicated/innovative nurse leader. Combined evidence based practices to provide personalized care and targeted towards optimal quality outcomes for clients
- Active nurse leader who facilitated a culture of safety to include enhancing safety processes/procedures for women's service line.
- Specialty certified to educate families on various forms of care. Includes newborn, breastfeeding techniques, and safety/emergency care.
- Coordinated and planned interdisciplinary care. Responsible for reviewing/ auditing charting and patient care plans. Ensured that all care needs were being met, including those related to medications, diagnostic testing, and education.

United States Air Force Operations Management, Communication and Information 2000 - 2011 (11 years)

Various locations (Active Duty, Air Guard)

Managed the process of planning, coordinating, and disseminating organization's data assets. Conducted information analyses to determine proper flow and life-cycle management of information. Operated/managed information systems to create, collect, process, disseminate, use, store, and dispose of information. Developed, provided, and educated staff on workflow capabilities and tools to comply with structured electronic processes while creating/developing ad hoc courses of actions. Approved and published content through automated publishing tools. Oversaw organization's compliance and management of AF Portal/collaboration tools. Managed publications and forms development, design, control, storage, acquisition and dissemination.

• Driving force in managing enlisted and officer evaluation programs.

- -- Instrumental in planning, development, and execution of training material for assigned personnel ensuring training requirements were met.
- Oversaw/monitored international merchant purchase authorization program contributing to squadron's error free rating during a non-notice inspection by finance directorate inspectors.
- Superior professional skills, leadership, and ceaseless efforts resulted in major contributions to the effectiveness/success of knowledge operations management office receiving excellent ratings for compliance and operations readiness inspections, "best seen to date."
- Developed skeleton layout plan for the implementation of electronic records, resulting in 100% uniformity and receiving excellent score in wing wide inspection.
- -- Trained records management personnel according to air force directives ensuring 100% compliance.
- Managed the Directorate/Commander of Operations' Federal automated system travel program of 55 operations personnel.
- Managed and mentored assigned and new staff, ensuring that training and education was in accordance with AF guidelines.

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Doctor of Nursing Practice - Executive, Administration & Leadership · (2018 - 2021)

University of St. Francis
Masters of Science in Nursing (2014)

The University of New Mexico
Bachelors of Science in Nursing (2009)

Airman Leadership Supervisory/Military Management School Management and Leadership (2005)

Community College of the Air Force

Operations, Communication and Information Management · (2000)